good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICICI Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited Q4 and Si 23
earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bhargav dasgupta MD and CEO
of the company Mr gopal balachandran CFO
and cro
issant Sanjeev mantri executive director
and Mr alok Agarwal executive director
please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future and more risk and
uncertainties which could cause the
results to defer materially from the
current views bring expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during this
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing start and 0 on your
Touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
I now had the conference over the Mr
bhargav dance Gupta MD and CEO ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited thank
you and over to you sir
thank you anirov and good evening to
each one of you thank you for joining
the earnings conference call of Isis
Lombard General Insurance company for Q4
and F5 2023 I will give you a view of
brief overview of the industry Trends
and developments that we have witnessed
in the past few months post this RCA
phone Mr gopal balachandran will share
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter and year ended March
21st 2023.
the Indian economy is showing signs of
resilience while the global economic
uncertain remains elevated dramatically
all the leading indicators are pointing
towards sustained momentum in the
economic activity however Persistence of
elevated inflation and advanced
economies tightening Financial
conditions and ongoing geopolitical
tensions may impact domestic growth
going forward
as for data published by CM the new
vehicle sales contribute deliver growth
year on year for Private Car however the
pent-up demand
seems to have settled commercial vehicle
segments continue to deliver robust
growths while the two wheeler segment in
terms of volumes is still below the
pre-pandemic level
health insurance continued that the
river overs growth the commercial lines
witnessed growth in line with the
current market environments the overall
growth of the industry was highest in
the last five years we remain optimistic
with the industry will continue to grow
given the favorable regulatory changes
low penetration and positive customers
sentiments
speaking of the performance the GI
industry delivered a gdpi growth of 16.4
percent for F5 2023
at the same time the underwriting
performance remained weak with the
combined ratio of the industry at 116.2
for nine months of this year as against
119.2 for nine month FY 2022
for motor business the combined ratio
for the industry was 123.5 for half year
of this year which improved to 818.9 for
Q3 f523 as for public disclosures while
there will be gradual signs of
improvement in the motor segment the
combined ratio remains higher than FY 22
levels which was at 115.6
you have already in the current
Financial year introduced various
reforms seeking to expand the market and
increase the penetration of insurance
products during the quarters The
Authority notified expensive management
and the payment of commission
regulations so opposing an aggregate
limit at a company level with essence of
1st April 2026.
moving to the business impact for us
during the quarters the company grew by
6.7 percent
including crop and and one one-off
transaction in the motor segment the
company grew by 12.6 percent as against
the industry growth X crop of 17.9
coming to the growth of key segments oh
sorry it interrupt you but there is a
slight disturbance coming from the line
participants
uh yes and now it's better okay uh so
I'll just repeat uh the last line that I
spoke
coming to the growth of the key segments
during that quarter in the commercial
line we experience robust growth driven
by growth of 15.9 percent of the SMA
segment
further during the year we accredited
market share across segments such as
engineering library and maintenance
market share in the fire signal in
addition to the above another
development in the commercial line
segment was the discontinuance of IRB
race as minimum rates in the fire
reinsurance treaties due to a regulatory
director
also the impact of global hardening on
reinsurance terms especially your
natural catastrophic catastrophic
protection was experienced by the
insurers during April 1 renewals we
believe that although this may create
short-term disruption in the long term
this is expected to be positive and
bring in underwriting discipline at the
same time for players like us who have
Capital brand and presence across
multiple lines of business at scale we
should benefit from this
in motor we review by 11.5 percent
excluding the one-off transaction the
growth was muted at 0.6 percent as
against the industry growth of 13.1
percent we continue to focus on
profitable sub segments using historical
granular data and rebalance your
portfolio result in a CV mix at 22.3
percent and two wheeler makes at 27.8
for FY 2823
similar to the previous year the overall
health segment continued to be the
fastest growing segment of the industry
during the quarter we grew at 31.1
percent which was higher than the
industry growth of 29.7
in group health the employer employee
segment the change in underlying
industry pricing sentiment resulted in
customers moving towards companies which
have better underwriting and service
capabilities
resulting in a group health segment to
grow by 35.7 during the quarter and 43.9
for the year
as a result of a continued investment in
retail Health distribution we have
outgrown the industry for Q4 uh fi 2023
with the growth of 19.4 percent and in
the month of March with the growth of 27
this was driven by business source
through retail health agency vertical
which grew at 30.9 further in the month
of February we undertook a price
increase in our retail Health Indemnity
renewal book at approximately about 19
percent
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop solution for all insurance and
wellness needs I'll take care of has
passed 4.6 million user downloads till
date the incremental download for the
quarter was close to 1 million
for Q4 of fi 23 water and water growth
of Premium Source through this app was
58.4 percent which is over the previous
quarter of Q3 of every fy23 thus
contributing
55.1 crore to gbpi for Q3 of FY 23 this
number was
347.9 million or 34.7 crore for Q2 it
was 27.44 crore and for q1 it was 10
crores
our bank insurance and key relationship
groups grew at 25.7 this quarter within
this is event distribution grew at 14.2
percent and the non ICC Bank
distribution grew at 32.2 percent post
pandemic the recovering credit growth
along with increasing wallet share in
distribution Partners acquired through
the demeriture has been the key growth
driver
our business source to a digital one
team who are 19.4 overall our digital
Focus has enabled us to increase our
digital revenues which includes the I'll
take care app to 3.14 billion which
accounts for 6.3 percent of our overall
GDK for the quarter we remain on track
and are focused on growth levers such as
Innovation digital advancements
launching new products strengthening our
distribution engine rationalizing cost
while scaling up our preferred lines of
business
I will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
Recently concluded quarter thanks Margo
friend uh good evening to each one of
you I will now give you a brief overview
of the financial performance of the
company for quarter four and FY 2023 we
have uploaded the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
cross direct premium income of the
company was rupees 210.25 billion in FY
2023 as against rupees 179.77 billion in
a 522 the growth of 17 against industry
growth of 16.4 percent
growth was primarily driven by growth in
the preferred segments the overall gdpa
of our Property and Casualty segment
grew by 18.9 at rupees 59.73 billion and
523 has against rupees 54 million fy22
on the retail side of the business GDP
of the motor segment was at rupees 85.82
billion in fy23 as against rupees 82.8
billion f522 registering a growth of 3.7
excluding the one-off transaction that
Bargo referred to the growth was at 6.9
percent
our agents including the point of sale
distribution count was around 1 lakh 13
000 as on March 31 2023 up from one lakh
six thousand one one nine as on December
31 2022. the advanced premium was rupees
32.17 billion as at 131 2023 as against
rupees 32.79 billion as at December 31
2022 resultantly combined ratio was 104
4.5 for the full year as against hundred
and eight point eight percent in FY 22
combined ratio for the quarter was
104.2 percent this year as against 103.2
percent in quarter four FY 22. our
investment assets Rose to rupees 431.8
billion at March 31 2023 up from rupees
414.51 billion at December 31 2022 our
investment leverage date of borrowings
was 4.15 times
at Mass 31 2023 as against 4.16 at
December 31 2022. investment income for
the full year was rupees 29.77 billion
as against rupees 30 billion in FY 2022
on a quarterly basis investment income
increased to 8.17 billion in Q4 fy23 as
against rupees 7.06 billion in Q4 F5
our capital gains net of impairment on
uh investment assets stood at rupees
4.53 billion in FY 2023 as compared to
rupees 7.38 billion in fy22 capital
gains in quarter four FY 23 was at
rupees 1.59 billion as compared to
rupees 1.36 billion in quarter four FY
22. our profit before tax blew by 25.5
percent at rupees 21.13 billion in f523
as against rupees 16.84 billion in FY
2022 whereas PBT grew by 39.5 at rupees
5.73 billion in Q4 fy23 as against
rupees 4.1 billion in q4fy 22.
consequently profit after tax grew by 36
percent at rupees 17.29 billion fy23 as
against rupees 12.71 billion in fy22
whereas profit after tax
grew by 39.8 percent at rupees 4.37
billion in Q4 fy23 up from rupees 3.13
billion in Q4 fy22
that includes the reversal of tax
provision of rupees 1.28 billion in Q2
F5 2023 the board of directors of the
company has proposed a final dividend of
rupees 5.5 per share for fy23 the
payment is however subject to approval
of shareholders in the issuing and
original meeting of the company the
overall dividend for FY 2023 including
the proposed final dividend is rupees 10
per share last year it was 9 rupees per
share written on average Equity was 17.7
in fy23 as it is 14.7 percent in FY 22
the return on average equity for the
quarter four FY 23 was 17.2 percent as
against 14 in Q4 f522 solvency ratio was
2.5 times at Mass 31 2023 as against
2.45 times at December 31 2022 continues
to be higher than the regulatory minimum
of 1.5 times
as I conclude I would like to reiterate
we continue to stay focused on driving
profitable growth sustainable value
creation and safeguarding interest of
policyholders are at at all times I
would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and now we
will be happy to take any questions that
you may have thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session anyone
who wishes to watch the question may
press star and one on their Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star and do
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
participants you may press star and one
to ask a question
the first question is from
bnk Securities please go ahead
in the recent conversations you have
mentioned that there has been some you
know small but positive development on
the pricing side in uh motor via OD uh
but despite that I think what we are
seeing uh uh you know in your numbers is
that there has been uh the growth in the
motor premium so just wanted to
understand sir uh what is playing out
there and uh what has resulted is this a
high base effect or anything else that
we need to understand to factor in this
these routes that we have seen in the
modern group and also sir really if you
can highlight the reason for the
mobility loss ratio being higher this
quarter because I checked the reserved
fragments and there seems to be
you scored
so the first one sworn up on the motor
won't damage uh growth numbers I think
uh in line with what we have been
talking about uh why we continue to be a
bit cautious given the fact that uh the
competitive intensity on motor stays
elevated having said that you're right
we did talk about maybe some bit of
easing in pricing that one had expected
uh to kind of play through on the motor
segment which is why when you look at
the industry combined ratios for the
half years industry combined was at
roughly about 124 percent
if you look at that number for quarter
tree that number was about 118 so
clearly I think there seems to be some
signs of a bit of easing in so far as
the industry participants are concerned
in so far as ICC Lombard I think if you
recollect what we had said was obviously
we continue to write the motor segment
through a combination of both new as
well as the relatively older segment and
as we have been explaining we have been
also looking at segments which are
slightly older which typically comes
with a slightly higher loss experience
and the relative cost of acquisition for
that particular segment is relatively
lower so fans from an Roe perspective it
made a lot of sense for us to look at
writing that part of the business and
hence to that extent you would possibly
see maybe the loss ratios slightly
elevated
having said that I think what we would
always urge is to not look at maybe any
numbers on a quarter on quarter basis
but rather look at it more on a full
year basis in terms of the opportunity
so that's one
on motor third party loss ratios again
we will continue to make the same stance
which is to say that in a given quarter
there are a lot of factors that
influence the loss experience and
therefore in so far as if you ask us
whether there has been any change in our
reserving philosophy or approach there
has been no change in the reserving
philosophy or approach and motor TP
being unlike some of the other segments
which are short tail in terms of loss
development as we know it's a relatively
long tale of claims and there again I
think we would again urge all of you to
look at numbers more on a full year
basis and if you look at on a full year
basis the motor third party loss ratio
for the current year stands at 72
percent
so that's a better reflection of the
loss experience as compared to looking
at the numbers on a quadrant quarter
basis just to add one more point to what
gopal said uh when you compare yui
numbers last year Q4 for us was a very
big quarter for uh in motor business
That Base has played played out in in
terms of the growth numbers for us this
quarter but otherwise in terms of
pushing price increases that we are
actually taking we are supposed to some
price increases we will see whether
others follow
okay uh got it sir uh also I mean in
terms of the overall cost structures are
uh I mean ideally I understand that Q4
is generally a retail heavy quarter and
hence our commission outgo uh is
generally much higher but this time the
net commission ratio is somewhere around
uh two percent uh two to two point two
percent and no number so is there any
impact of the one-off transaction in
this if you could highlight the reason
and uh also uh the one of transaction if
I were to triangulate the number
somewhere in the pnl how how should I
you know look look for it
so attrition so far as uh the net
commission is concerned I think there is
uh some there is definitely nothing
which is more one-off uh we obviously
see cyclicality in some of the outcomes
when you see on a quarter on quarter
performance uh particularly for example
on some of the uh commercial line
portfolios we get to see the experience
of how good or bad the portfolio outcome
has been that gets demonstrated at the
end of financial year particularly in
quarter four and hence to that extent
you will possibly be able to see some
element of maybe profit commission that
typically gets recognized in Q4 but
nothing there's nothing which is like
one off and in general as we have been
talking about on the commercial line our
portfolio experience has been in that
sense profitable and therefore the terms
of commissions that we get from the
reinsurers is what has possibly resulted
in maybe the net commission ratio
reflecting a different number
but otherwise there is no one-off in so
far as this particular recognition is
concerned
request to join the queue again for a
follow-up question
the next question is from the line of
Avinash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead
yeah hi uh good evening uh two questions
our first is more on the regulatory side
where regulator has sort of uh bringing
of I would say a weight Clause saying
that benefit of a direct distribution to
be passed on to the uh policyholders now
here my question is that is the
regulator sort of a saying uh to you or
the industry that okay you have to have
a kind of a direct version of the same
policy or if not I mean I'm saying that
simply that okay what if a health policy
a retail policy a customer coming for
Renewal now are you supposed to pass on
that if the customer is willing to pay
to your branch as your portal directly
are you willing or are you required now
to pass on the this dip commission
difference I mean I am talking for
Renewal where I mean there is definitely
no almost no cost in terms of direct I
can understand the cost on the new
issuance but when a customer is coming
for the renewal directly for help I mean
virtually there is no distribution cost
involved so I mean are you going to pass
on are required that's number one and
stick in the on the you know extensive
management side I mean of course the new
regulation has come but even for the
existing regulation perspective I mean
for your scale the 31 kind of a reported
Express of management it looks uh I mean
there's something I mean uh the
operating leverage uh is kind of a bit
evasive and to add to that if I see the
p l there is some close to 900 support
crores or like you know or close to four
percent of your uh gross premium that is
being charged with say a holder's
account whereas the ratio says 31
percent so why is I mean uh at least
from the ratio it does not appear as you
have breached uh experience of
management by that kind of amount so
what the sort of connection I am missing
here the other two questions thank you
Google will take the second question let
me answer the first
I think the direction that the regulator
is taking is
making the regulation more principle
based and leaving in independent
companies with lot more flexibility to
manage their business in the way they
think appropriate
uh everything that you're that they're
doing at least our read of the matter is
there giving insurance companies a bit
more Choice than what we had in the past
so even when it comes to the fact that
you can give a lower commission that is
also a choice given which in the past we
were not explicitly given
uh as a company we still have been
giving a lower price in the online
policies by two and a half to five
percent so that's the practice that
we've been been doing and we will
continue to do that coming to what will
happen because of this I think you know
it is too early to comment on how uh
Market would uh would adjust to these
changes uh but as I said my sense is
that it is uh giving a lot more
flexibility to us and a different
companies will plan out what they want
to do with these flexibilities
you know do remember that the in certain
products the agent even if let's say
customer reviews online sometimes agents
do play a role in recommending that and
driving that behavior
may not be true for everything but a lot
of times it is that is how it is but as
I said more importantly it's a choice
given to insurance companies you plan
their business strategy
so Avinash on the second point
I think the number what you're saying of
31.4 percent is Basis uh for quarter
four based on regulatory stipulated way
of computing the expense of management
ratio so there if you see the
denominator as what is being put out on
the footnotes it's based on the gross
direct premium income
having said that the threshold on the
expense of management works on the basis
of gross return premium so when you kind
of compute the numbers on the basis of
gross return premium that 31.4 percent
will stand
revised to let's say 29.5 which is
within the threshold of compliance in so
far as the limits on expensive
management is concerned the same number
on a four-liar basis what you are seeing
of 29.6 which is again based on Gross
direct premium income in line with the
requirement of the regulation which is
on Gross return premium that number will
be looking like 29 which is again within
the threshold on limits that has been
laid down by expense of management
so that's one so your second point on
there seems to be an amount of let's say
close to about 900 crores which is
reflected as a part of the p l uh
disclosures uh what the regulator is
also under the earlier regime which is
valid until March 23 and also stipulated
one compliance is at an aggregate level
which is what I explained very well
within the limits on laid down with the
regulation to as you know they are also
laid down limits for individual lines of
businesses and in case if there are any
line of businesses where possibly the
limits on expenses slightly elevated
then to that extent from a disclosure
perspective so much of the excess is
required to be separately disclosed as a
part of the p l numbers but when the
computation of the combined ratio
happens it factors in for all the
operating expenses that we encourage the
company so it's more a disclosure that
is stipulated by the regulation as
compared to the fact that it is not a
case where at a company level we have
exceeded the limits on extensive
management we are well within the
threshold okay I think a quick of
follow-up I mean sorry a different one
on the reinsurance side if I see there
are three kind of a changes happening
one of the global hardening and
audiences Market the second thing I see
you know that kind of a regulator
nursing the primary ensure that okay go
ahead without any sort of a relationship
prescribed or flow rate that was a kind
of a practice in commercial lines of
course that's the kind of a second
impact and thirdly with the new um
regulation coming on the gwp basis uh
probably I mean the way some primary
companies or even the insurance
companies solid sitting are starting to
use as businesses where commissions
might be I mean get a bit disturbed the
kind of a Resource Commission they would
be paying because now this I guess new
um regulation of 30 will be applicable
on all these three things that you know
a bit of dislocation commissions uh you
know that they're used to have driven
flow rates not really mandated rather uh
you know issues trying to choose and
thirdly the global reason is Market
hardening all this net net how is going
to sort of a impact the you know that
yours or the industry Behavior as far as
the commercial line or kind of a heavily
reinforced back line are concerned
so no you've there's a great Point
Avinash and we've been talking about the
fact that in commercial line there will
be a fair amount of uh change even in
the last quarter before these things
were explicitly clear we were talking
about the fact that some of these
changes would have impact of course we
couldn't anticipate the retarding on the
reinsurance side till that time but
that's now evident
so the point that you're making is very
absolutely valid so globally if you look
at rates in certain markets it's gone up
by you know 50 60 in our Market it's
also gone up by 45 to 60 for most
players in the market uh that's an input
cost to us largely we uh the on the
non-proportion thread the cost has gone
up the commissions that the insurers
give on the proportional side has gone
down so it's a it's a it's a significant
increase in cost the second is as you
like you said that pricing is largely
not mandated to be in line with the
burning cost of the industry so
individual companies can charge whatever
they want to
and hence there is a risk that the
pricing can drop
our senses and you know um of course is
there but at the end of the day finally
it's within you know overall combined
and we see here was a very positive
development uh in the sense that uh you
know it's expected from the regulator
that companies will reduce their
expensive management even if their
videos are threshold and those above the
threshold have to bring it down to 30
percent within three years so that
should drive positive behavior you know
anticipation so that um I don't see as a
negative in this sense so the first two
perspective uh you know I think the way
we are seeing the market in the first
month
the or the second issue in terms of
rates coming down uh episcopically one
or two cases have come down but on
Aggregates the rates haven't come down
as much as we would be worried about
it's come down a little bit but nothing
material
uh our sense is that you know usually it
will is a big month uh gives a sense of
where the market is headed and in future
also we are not anticipating a major
drop in commercial rates in the market
simply because the industry cannot
afford to you know as you rightly
identified on one side the cost has gone
up and it's not as if the combined ratio
for the industry was very healthy so I
don't think the industry has too much of
a wherewithal to you know reduce prices
uh much maybe there's one or two
episodes you know cases that will happen
but not that scale
the last one that I'll make is that you
know if you check certain companies go
very aggressive on the property side and
in effect end up burning their treaty uh
the reinsurance market with this
hardening that we are seeing and the
attitude hardening ever since the
rituals don't have appetite to give a
city capacity which you can keep burning
and that's what you feel in the market
this year right so if that happens if
any company does that our senses in the
next year they will find it very
difficult to get proper treaty capacity
I think this is some companies travel uh
you know more will struggle if that
happens and if that happens I think we
are on a you know better Wicket because
we have the
writing we should stand to benefit
our experience or our estimate for the
year uh you know we've been giving a
guidance as a company that over the next
two years we want to bring it down to
102. we are not changing the guidance in
spite of this uh cost increase on the
reinsurance side
thank you very much
to the next question
the next question is from the line of
prayer Shane from motilal Oswald please
go in
oh yeah hi good evening everyone a few
questions from my side uh firstly uh
could you highlight as to when this
one-off transaction happened in February
and there would be some income and which
line item does that income uh income
sits in uh secondly uh the is there some
seasonal between motor TP loss ratios
because in past three years we've seen
Q4 being far more elevated than Q3 uh
and in one of the I think if I reconnect
well in one of the fourth quarters you
had mentioned that this was that was
because of adverse judgments uh adverse
judgments in that case and thirdly uh
we've seen a sharp a good decline in
terms of absolute cost for advertisement
and publicity sales promotion employee
remuneration as you know the recent
decline in terms of sequentially uh so
what is the kind of Runway that we
should think about the from uh for your
perspective of next year
so Praise on the one-off transaction
which we have been kind of explaining
that's something that has happened in
quarter four and uh this is in that
sense something that we did in line with
what let's say other Market participants
have been possibly doing it in the
current year or maybe in the early areas
as well
it's a commercially viable transaction
that we have kind of undertaken and
hence to that extent the outcome of the
transaction will be reflected in the
overall underwriting result
uh when you look at the aggregate
numbers
uh in so far as your motor third-party
uh loss ratio trend line of seasonality
between quarter four there is in that
sense not any specific seasonality that
typically gets attached so for example
if you recollect two years back which is
in fy21 at that point of time when we
had possibly seen elevated levels of
motor third-party losses loss ratios
being higher they kind of talk to the
market to say that we did see at that
point of Time incrementally new Supreme
Court judgments that had come through in
terms of defining the basis on which
compensation will get paid to victims of
accidents and hence to that extent when
we kind of evaluated that particular
book we obviously wanted to make sure
that we did not know in which direction
that would take shape and so far as
future settlements are concerned but
having said that given that you always
followed a prudent approach to reserving
we obviously wanted to strengthen the
reserves at that point of time and hence
to that extent you would have possibly
seen maybe an elevated quarter foreign
depending on how things have come back
in terms of normalcy because last two
years typically has been periods where
we have seen in different quarters Kobe
experiences play out and ends to that
extend the scale of operations will
possibly also be a function of what kind
of loss experience that one exhibits
and thirdly as we keep saying one should
always look at particularly long tail
line of businesses experiences more on
ideally over longer years but definitely
not on a quarter on quarter basis you
should look at it look at more on annual
numbers as compared to let's say looking
at a quarter on quarter 10.
the last point of yours I think as we
have kept saying uh we do kind of look
at productivity and efficiency in the
overall means of doing business and
hence is where we are kind of spoken
about what Virgo just mentioned where
clearly the direction that you want to
take is to bring down the overall
combined from the current levels of
closer to 104 that we have been
operating down to let's say 102 over the
next two years and within that we are
extremely focused on looking at every
element of cost whether it is the cost
of doing business or even any other
Investments that were kind of looking
through uh so in that sense it is not
that there is uh any significant change
we continue to make investments in the
health agency platform that we have
spoken about we continue to stay
invested in digital and in line with our
recent uh digital day that we had which
we kind of shared with all of you we
continue to stay invested in the various
technology transformation projects as
well so hence to that extent that is how
we should look at uh in terms of the
loss in terms of the expense ratio trend
line nothing specific that is there as a
one-off in so far as a quarter four
numbers is considered
thank you
thank you very much
the next question is I'm from the line
of sharia from clsa please go ahead
hi thank you for the opportunity so I
have much of my questions are answered I
have one now missing doubt that the the
insurance that get that that gets added
to the gross direct premium
um and eventually it becomes gross
premium written is high for fourth
quarter seasonally or
um because even last year fourth quarter
it was a higher number this year again
it's a higher number if you can easily
understand this thing
so that's so nothing's nothing unusual
Shreya in that sense I think we look at
any again the reinsurance invert is
again an opportunity that one please
depending on how we are able to get
businesses for a particular period
um so in general yes there could be some
kind of a seasonality attached to it for
example you would see on the corporate
side to be significantly heavy in q1
let's see retail to be significantly
heavy in Q3 you may see Q2 and Q3
seasonality attached to crop so
therefore different businesses exhibit
and maybe retail health for the matter
of fact to some extent I would say
attached to some seasonality in Q4 as
well so hence there are different lines
of businesses that exhibit seasonality
and hence to that extent the reinsurance
inward could also be one of them but at
the end of the day whichever segment
that we are talking about we obviously
look at it from the ultimate lens of
profitable growth
seasonality attached to it as an example
I am not saying in the context of
reinsurance inward even on the direct
side on retail Health you will possibly
see Q4 to be a slightly seasonally
higher quarter
uh reinsurance invert could be a mix of
business across different segments it
need not be necessarily only held
okay okay okay got it yeah that was my
only question
thank you
next question is from the line of nidesh
chain from investec please go ahead
uh thanks for the opportunities there's
three questions firstly on the combined
ratio uh what is the impact of this
one-off transaction on our combined
ratio of 10 or 4.2 percent for the
quarterback uh secondly uh what is the
health agency gdpi in absolute terms uh
for f523 and q4fi 23
and lastly uh we have got access to HDFC
bank and access bank if you can share
how is the progress there what is the
business which we have been able to
Source from these channels uh in f523 or
q4f23 these are three questions
so let me increase the third one I think
we are quite happy with uh
uh you know remarks uh most of the
distribution channels that we got
through the merger with battery uh we
are quite happy with the progress that
we've made uh in those specific uh
partners that you're talking about the
large Banker partners that we've got in
both these uh
relationships with uh increase the share
of wallet uh in fact month and month
quarter and quarter even during this
year visually when we had announced the
transaction to now it has been a
significant increase in uh share of
quality
the first two questions
yeah so in so far as maybe I will take
the second podcast uh in terms of the
split of uh Health gdpi that for the
full year is that about uh
47.82 billion rupees that's for fi23 and
for fy22 that number was 34.87
on the point on the impact of combined
issue nitesh the fact that it's a
commercially viable transaction is why
we have done that and ends to that
extent in terms of it does not have any
uh material impact in so far as the
overall combined ratio is considered
thank you
so there's minor positive impact on
combined ratio it should that is the way
we should do better that is correct
and then on the health agency I was
talking about health agency gdpi uh for
f523 or f522 so uh 47.82 billion is
Total Health uh GDP right health agency
GDP I was looking for
so the health agency gdpi for the full
year stands at about 5.6 billion
thanks
thank you
next question is from the line of
madhukar from nawama please go ahead
hi good evening thank you for taking my
question
first uh you know
um on the regulatory chain side the
expensive management now allowable
differentiate between the sahis and the
genuine Sorrows as far as the health
business is concerned
30 percent
does that
create some sort of uh you know uneven
things uh like uh uneven uh field uh for
the industry and for you guys
uh and second uh you know I see that
your investment income uh has improved
considerably in Q4
and also if you look at the Q3 balance
sheet versus uh Q4 balance sheet the
unrealized gains have dropped
significantly from about 550 crores to
about 213 crores
so has there been uh you know
an increase in uh realized gains in this
in this quarter which is resulted in a
strong investment income performance
those would be my two questions yeah
yeah so um if you look at the eom I mean
you know I think principally any
difference in our Arbitrage in
regulation is not uh you know something
that is uh useful but having said that I
think Studies have a genuine problem in
the sense that they are single Product
Company so we can defray cost across
multiple businesses they can't
when we look at the fact that as a
multi-line company we write different
types of businesses where the cost of
distribution is lower we don't see a big
disadvantage uh because he's a 35
percent and we have 30. because we have
other products where the cost of
distribution would be lower uh then
let's say the health business even for
us the health business would be the we
have some advantage in the other lines
of business
uh on the second question on the
investment side
um
yeah so uh so if you look at on the uh
Mark to Market side uh the drop in from
550 crores so let's say 200 crores uh
and in that context the point that you
asked us together there is a significant
increase in capital gains for this
quarter vis-a-vis let's say quarter four
of last year so there is in that sense
there is not a significant increase if
you look at Q4 of the current years the
capital gains stood at about
1.59 as compared to 1.36 billion which
was the capital gain that one had seen
in quarter four of last year
uh to your other point on the quarter on
quarter increase in the overall
investment income that is exactly what
we have been talking about
to say that any increase in the
interstate regime obviously ogres well
for us given the fact that as the
portfolio starts to get rebalanced in
terms of uh mix of investment assets
which gets invested at a relatively
higher yield you will start seeing on an
incremental quarters maybe the interest
income getting reflected appropriately
so that's the only reason why you see
possibly the increase in you know
investment income otherwise there is uh
nothing else that is attached to those
numbers just one more point to add to
what gopal said on the investment side
uh I think you know we were probably
um
uh we you know we were correct in
expecting the interested movement in the
market and at this point in time it
seems to be a current decision where we
increase the uh the duration of our
portfolio in the first half of the year
and that's also playing out uh you know
because of that interested key in that
real Google is talking about we've been
able to take advantage because we
increase the duration of the portfolio
in the first half of the year
right on this one thank you
thanks
thank you
next question is from the line of
subratim datta from Ambit Capital please
go ahead
hello thanks for the opportunity so I
have two questions one on the health uh
retail Health Science could you talk
about the investment opportunities that
you are looking at going forward also
what these investment opportunities
include an acquisition to you know or
drive the retail health and air channel
faster that's first secondly
on the you know
the URL and if I look at it on a or you
know compare it with the net written
premium then that ratio comes out to
around 56 for FY 23 basically it has
been around the 58 59 previously so it
seems like you are uh booking more
revenues in fy23 so how should I look at
it if you could give some clarity around
that that would be very helpful
so I'll take the first two and I'll
request gopal to take the last one
um in terms of health detail as we've
said that this is an area that we want
to uh sustain uh our investment we've
talked about the man part that we've
added during this year and we also said
that we were we wanted to see the
productivity Gain come through uh
clearly the signs are very very positive
if you see our second half growth in
retail Health business we generally are
performing the market uh having said
that we don't think they've reached the
true level of productivity that we
expect them to them so there is still
some traction on the investment that
we've made in terms of improvement in
the top line from that channel that
we've added
what we've decided to do is as we go
through the year we would look at how uh
you know where we are reaching with that
investment and we will uh you know
opportunistically add more resources to
see that to ensure that the investment
uh uh Focus remains on building the
distribution as we've said over the last
few years our retail Health uh market
share is uh you know must work on an
average and our plan is to Endeavor is
too over the years you know build it up
so that Focus remains uh with regard to
acquisition uh you know I don't want to
get into specific conversation about any
you know one segment or one one specific
company I think we've always been saying
that uh if there are uh you know viable
opportunities in the market where you
know an opportunity which gives us
access to our new distribution or a new
business
has also comes with the reasonable price
we are always open but there is nothing
specific that we are looking at at this
point in time
and uh to the uh third question on the
urr I think uh URS we have been
explaining even in the earlier quarters
is purely a function of uh earning the
premiums over the contract period uh and
hence to that extent uh depending on
again as I was explaining in responsible
earlier calls there are certain lines of
businesses which could possibly depict
in some quarters maybe a faster earning
uh so for example you will see maybe the
crop insurance segment typically
operates for particular seasons not that
we are writing a very large proportion
of that particular book but in terms of
any impact that one would see on the
Network premium you could see some
sequentiality attached to it but
otherwise urr is purely a function of
the way the portfolio gets earned over
the contract period and yes if you are
if you were to see last year for example
in fy22 the overall growth was only
about 4.7 percent whereas if you look at
our growth for the current year it's at
about 17 so that's again a factor that
one will have to take into consideration
when you look at earnings of urr over a
period of time there is no there is in
that sense uh nothing one-offs which is
there as a part of the unexpired
exclusive numbers
thank you
thank you next question is from line of
sanket Gora from avender spark please
Cohen
yes thank you thank you for the
opportunity
I wanted to understand uh what exactly
you are going to do with the crop
insurance business in fi 24 because
because today this year is the last year
for the access business what you
acquired so so given given the um rules
are around uh and and if you intend to
focus more on retail business which are
Optics intensive do we go a little
aggressive on the crop business in the
current year that's that's the first
question
see here so let me answer that so are we
going will we go aggressive on crop
business just because of eom uh
flexibility the answer is no uh we had
said at the beginning of or even last
year last couple of years that you know
post the acquisition we have said that
we will continue to have some exposure
to the crop business now given that
overall Market has improved there are
new schemes which are coming in uh and
the capacity in the market which is the
you know total number of players in the
market have reduced but we have been
clear that it will be roughly about 4.4
to five percent of our business that
narrative does not change we are not
changing any of those uh objectives just
because of UN
got it and and
given given uh the reinsurance market as
you highlighted has hardened and
probably the commercial lines
potentially could see a lower
profitability in the current year
because of the rules changes or on um
rules so so uh the Glide path what you
have mentioned that 104 combined
gradually improving to 102 by 525 uh
despite competitive intensity increasing
in in few profitable lines uh you still
still continue to maintain that one zero
two by 525 will be achieved or or this
could be a deviation
so that's what we said earlier in the
first our you know our objective hasn't
changed uh yes while in commercial lines
the profitability may not be in line
with what we have in the past but at the
same time we've taken a lot of calls
during the year which will play through
in the future is our expectation
um you know actions that you take now
helps you in the in the next year so we
are uh we are reasonably optimistic that
we will continue to deliver on that
black part that we've talked about when
it comes to commercial lines also uh you
know I think one of the things that you
which happens on the ground is that
there's a lot of calls that are taken at
a client level profitability so if you
are making a bit more money in fire you
may be a bit uh relaxed in pricing your
group health or Marine because you're
looking at a work portfolio
profitability
so if let's say fire profitability comes
down Google profitability or rather you
know the aggression of the group health
should reduce so those are the
expectation that we've had that we have
and you know some of those changes we've
seen in the group health side as you see
we've not seen an improvement in Marine
num you know rates as yet but overall we
believe that we will continue to manage
the uh you know commercial line business
profitably the combination May
deteriorate a little bit but that's
something that will make up from the
other lines of business whereas this
year was uh very stressed here in terms
of combination some of those lines
lastly the health investment that we
made
uh you know that that was a cost which I
think gopal has been talking about yeah
as that channel becomes more productive
we will get some you know benefits there
uh some of the channels that we got from
bharti AXA by the uh integration you
know there were early days of investment
into including some of the you know
large distribution Partners yeah those
are all beginning to come within
reasonable numbers in terms of combined
so all put together we are reasonably
considered about the numbers that we're
talking about
and for the full year and and uh and
given the price hike you have taken 19
percentage I believe it is both for new
and the renewal part uh then then
um uh can we expect a significant
Improvement in the retail lottery show
because because 19 Hospital inflation
looks little unlikely so so the benefit
will be there in fi 24 uh is it safe to
assume that way
so the first part uh
uh uh as usual so far as quarter four uh
Health uh ghi loss ratios are concerned
that's at 93.2
and so the retail Indemnity loss ratios
for the quarter is about 61 and if you
recollect even in the last quarter uh
when when I think you had only asked
what has been the last ratios we had
kind of talked about saying that the
group pulse will possibly end the year
with the loss ratio of close at about 95
so if you look at a four year basis the
ghi book loss ratio stands at about 95.
and the retail Indemnity loss ratio
stands at about 64 percent
uh so that's a breakup in so far as the
loss numbers are concerned your second
point on uh the increase in the pricing
uh the increase in pricing is with
respect to the renewal book
um it's not that it's on the entire book
that's one has applied the uh increase
in pricing but having said that yes to
some extent there will be an improvement
in the overall loss experience but at
the same time as you rightly mentioned
there is always an element of Health
inflation that one sees and going ahead
in fy24 we obviously will also have to
see what kind of a business mix that one
is able to source so there are various
factors that would influence the overall
loss number as we have said even in the
past like in general we believe the
retail Health Indemnity books should
kind of operate at a loss ratio range
which would be between 65 to 70 percent
next question is from the reign of core
of single from Apex management please go
ahead
yeah hi thanks for taking my question uh
just one question from my side uh so for
the investment work that we have what's
the uh average maturity
and also uh what's the difference
roughly between the yield that we are
realizing on the on the investment book
right now excluding capital gains and uh
and and the incremental yield that we
can invest by maintaining the same
average duration thank you
so the the duration of the book at the
end of the year fi 23 was 4.99 uh this
is slightly lower duration than what we
had at the end of nine months because
you know in the month of March we had a
very good influence into the portfolio
largely because uh the March numbers
from a business perspective are positive
and also the corporate business some of
the you know premium comes in so that
money obviously was not invested we
didn't have enough time to invest in the
long division one so that's sitting on
cash so hence the duration of portfolio
was slightly lower than what it was uh
as on nine months so it's about 4.99
roughly about five a YTM of the
portfolio is is carrying an yield of
over 7.2 percent
good morning thank you
thank you
next question is from the line of neeraj
social from UBS Securities please go
ahead
hi so uh what did you know uh our
thoughts
um are we experiencing the TV getting
shorter and that's true are we going to
release reserves and that is considered
into our Target combined ratio
uh the answer short answer is no uh as
in it's not you know it's a factor in
our Target combined ratio we are still
not assuming any change in the
underlying pattern as we spoke last time
you know the what's happening on the
ground kind of Remains the Same we've
had different judgments in different
High courts some judgments in the favor
of insurance industry some judgments not
so favor in favor of Industry so what we
are what we are is we are observing the
trends there are certain months where it
seems like it is accelerating certain
months the data is not very clear
so as we've been saying that we want to
watch this data for some time I think
what we'll have to see is cases that has
got reported with beyond the six month
period obviously we are contesting all
of that we will have to see in the
course how that plays through uh but we
are not assuming any benefit though we
remain reasonably hopeful that in the
longer term this will come uh you know
uh the courts will rule in favor of the
insurance industry because this is a lot
of the land but at this point in time we
are not factoring anything in the second
thing that you will remember in PP is
that we've not seen a price site right
and in TP we assume a certain claim
inflation as a as a norm as a company
and that came in fashion increases
something that we have continued to
assume as human for the coming years so
uh so not only are you not taking a
benefit we are also assuming a inflation
in the pp claims which is what we've
been doing over the years
[Music]
new pricing yeah so let us wait for them
to come so this is of course something
that you know uh you know the central
Ministry mods will have to give so we
have to wait for something to come
through as of now we have no uh
clarification about you know the
increased uh or any formulas used
and the second uh my question is
though optically it's going to be much
lower given the fact that the insurance
have been there so fourth quarter last
year so we had a lower Opex on nwpe uh
how do we how to should we think about
it uh in absolute amount also is
actually lower so is it sustainable or
do we think that the related like green
jump up or it's a fourth quarter
phenomenon
that will be helpful foreign
in terms of absolute numbers
again there as we keep saying uh you
should again look at more the combined
ratios of the overall operations because
different segments again will exhibit uh
breakdowns of that combined differently
I mean there are portfolios which could
be high on LR but relatively let's say
lower cost of acquisition and conversely
the other way around as well so
obviously we'll have to wait and see how
the portfolio build up takes place in
fy24
but as we have said clearly the
objective is we would want to kind of
stay on that glided path of combined
coming down from 104 to 102. and
secondly what we are seeing is obviously
encouraging science is some of the
Investments that we spoke about is
particularly on the retail health agency
franchise those are starting to play out
as you would have in let's say most of
the recent months our growth percentages
have been even faster than even the
Standalone Health company so clearly
those signs are getting exhibited but
having said that we continue to stay
invest in building that franchise which
will again mean expensing of cost
upfront and the benefit of revenues
coming through over a period of time so
a better trajectory to look is to look
at more the combined issues rather than
looking at just the uh let's say
expensive Management number on a
standalone basis
if you wanted to understand uh
foreign
broader range I think if you look at the
loss ratios they have kind of stayed in
the range of between let's say 70 to 75
in that kind of threshold uh so again as
I said that's again a function of
depending on what segments of business
is one able to see us and uh area of
opportunity and hence I mean very
difficult to kind of tell you as to what
could be the loss ratio uh number that
we will be kind of working with what we
are largely targeting is the combined
ratio threshold to come down 202 over
the next two year period
thank you next question is from the line
of question from Kodak Mahindra please
go in
uh thanks for taking my question uh I'm
looking at the advanced premium uh you
know figures and uh you know for last
couple of quarters this is actually not
been going up if it's come down a little
bit uh you know over the last three
quarters uh this is despite the fact
that you're actually being going faster
in Moto GP so
if you look at uh
in general I think the relative growth
for us on the overall motor has been
kind of uh slightly lower than the
market as what you have seen from public
data uh and relatively if you see the
growth on third party a large part of
the third party grows for us again which
is a thought through approach of
increasing the commercial vehicles
portfolio and there obviously the
commercial vehicle portfolio is not a
long-term third party book it's more on
private car and two wheelers is where
the portfolio typically has a longer
term tenure commercial vehicle portfolio
in the current context operates with the
one year term and that's primarily the
reason why you possibly do not see in
that sense a significant change in the
overall Advanced premium numbers as and
when obviously we see the market coming
back as what we have seen some early
signs on let's say on the private card
side we should definitely possibly get
to see the advanced premium numbers uh
maybe increasing
thank you
sorry to interruption
ladies and gentlemen will take that as a
last question I will now hand the
conference or the Mr bhargav dance Gupta
for closing comments
oh thank you thank you everyone for
joining the call so late in the evening
uh and look forward to engaging with you
uh over the next few days thank you
again thank you good night
thank you very much
on behalf of ICICI lumbar General
Insurance Company Limited that concludes
this conference thank you for joining us
you may now disconnect your lines
thank you